OK so let's continue and look at another situation and another common phrase we can use to express ourselves
好的，让我们继续看看另一种情况和另一个我们可以用来表达自己的常用短语
in that situation.
在那种情况下。
So have you ever experienced a co-worker another person maybe getting fired and then another person
所以你有没有经历过一个同事，另一个人可能被解雇，然后另一个人
your colleague said something negative or insulting about them and you don't like that actually can
你的同事说了一些关于他们的负面或侮辱性的话，而你不喜欢那实际上可以
work for a situation where anybody says something and you don't like that they said it and you think
适用于任何人说了些什么而您不喜欢他们说的话而您认为的情况
it's not appropriate that they said it.
他们这样说是不合适的。
You think it's wrong that they said it.
你认为他们这样说是错误的。
You want to express that you think that.
你想表达你的想法。
Well don't say don't say that.
好吧，不要说不要那样说。
I suppose you could but there is a better way.
我想你可以，但有更好的方法。
So your co-worker just got fired and another co-worker makes an insulting comment about them.
所以你的同事刚被解雇，另一位同事对他们发表了侮辱性的评论。
The person who got fired like they were useless anyway.
无论如何，被解雇的人就像他们没用一样。
Well that's not nice that's mean.
好吧，这不好，这很卑鄙。
I mean that's cruel pay.
我的意思是，这是残酷的报酬。
That's what we can use to express our emotion our sort of surprise our shock.
这就是我们可以用来表达我们的情感的东西，我们有点惊讶我们的震惊。
Hey that's a bit uncalled for uncalled for uncalled for.
嘿，这有点不合时宜。
Nobody's perfect.
没有人是完美的。
So when something happens or something is said and the thing that happens with the thing that is said
所以当某事发生或某事被说出时，所发生的事情与所说的事情
is maybe rude inappropriate not the right thing in this situation.
在这种情况下，这可能是粗鲁的不恰当而不是正确的事情。
Just not good.
就是不好。
And you want to declare it use uncalled for.
并且您想声明它使用不需要。
Could be an action for example.
例如，可能是一个动作。
You're watching a sports game and one player just punches another player.
您正在观看一场体育比赛，而一名球员只是打了另一名球员。
You could say whoa whoa whoa.
你可以说哇哇哇。
That was uncalled for.
那是不必要的。
He shouldn't have done that.
他不应该那样做。
That was not necessary.
那是没有必要的。
Basically the meaning of this is not necessary not necessary unneeded.
基本上这个意思是没必要没必要没必要。
OK.
好的。
You don't need to say something negative about the co-worker who just laughed right.
你不需要对刚刚笑得对的同事说一些负面的话。
I mean they just got fired.
我的意思是他们刚刚被解雇了。
They're probably having a terrible day.
他们可能度过了糟糕的一天。
Why do you need to say something negative about them.
为什么你需要对他们说一些负面的话。
That's really uncalled for.
这实在是太没有必要了。
But at the same time it's polite.
但同时也是礼貌的。
If I say that to my co-worker who said the negative thing the insulting thing and that's pretty uncalled
如果我对我的同事这么说，他说了负面的话，那是侮辱性的话，那是完全没有必要的
for I'm being kind of polite but still mentioning that I'm not okay with the comment then maybe my co-worker
因为我有点礼貌，但仍然提到我对评论不满意，那么也许是我的同事
will say Yeah yeah I'm sorry I shouldn't have said that I shouldn't I shouldn't have said that I shouldn't
会说 是 是 对不起 我不应该说我不应该 我不应该说我不应该
have said it.
已经说过了。
Maybe they apologize whatever but uncalled for is the expression that I use to bring up the fact that
也许他们会道歉，但我用这种表达方式来提出这样一个事实，但这是不必要的
it's not OK.
不行。
It's really common for actions for things that are said.
对于所说的事情采取行动真的很常见。
One more example of uncalled for.
又一个不合时宜的例子。
Might be the companies companies decision to ban band means you're not allowed to do that to ban shorts
可能是公司决定禁止乐队意味着你不能这样做来禁止短裤
is uncalled for.
是不必要的。
Maybe we work in a company that's pretty informal generally and a lot of people wear shorts when they
也许我们在一家通常非常非正式的公司工作，很多人在上班时都穿短裤
come into work OK.
上班OK。
But the company has decided no they will not allow shorts.
但该公司已决定不，他们不会允许短裤。
Well I don't like that my opinion.
好吧，我不喜欢我的意见。
That's not OK so I'll say hey this decision to ban shorts is uncalled for unnecessary unnecessary.
那不行，所以我会说，嘿，这个禁止短裤的决定是不必要的，是不必要的。
So that's how we use it a similar expression to this that we can use in the co-worker situation is like
这就是我们使用它的方式，我们可以在同事情况下使用与此类似的表达方式，就像
this is that is that really necessary.
这才是真正必要的。
That really necessary so we can actually say is that necessary to express our feeling.
这真的很有必要，所以我们实际上可以说是表达我们的感受所必需的。
It's the same meaning it's the same meaning when you're doing this what you're doing is you're sticking
这是同一个意思 当你在做什么的时候是同一个意思你在做的是你坚持
up for that person to defend someone usually in words is to stick up for them.
为那个人辩护通常用言语来捍卫某人就是为他们挺身而出。
If somebody says something bad about your family member what will you do.
如果有人说你家人的坏话，你会怎么做。
You'll say hey that's uncalled for as My my brother you're talking about what am I doing.
你会说，嘿，这是不必要的，因为我的兄弟，你在谈论我在做什么。
I'm sticking up for my family.
我为我的家人挺身而出。
Well maybe I'm sticking up for this person who got fired.
好吧，也许我会支持这个被解雇的人。
They're not even here.
他们甚至都不在这里。
But I'm still sticking up for them because the comment was made behind their back.
但我仍然支持他们，因为评论是在他们背后发表的。
They weren't there.
他们不在那里。
They can't defend themselves.
他们无法为自己辩护。
They didn't hear it the comment was made behind their back.
他们没有听到评论是在他们背后发表的。
So I want to stick up for them.
所以我想为他们挺身而出。
So whenever you defend someone with your words usually you're sticking up for them.
因此，每当你用你的话语为某人辩护时，你通常都会为他们挺身而出。
You're saying hey no not OK I protect the people behind me.
你是说嘿不不行我保护我身后的人。
That's the idea anyway very common expression both this one and uncalled for.
无论如何，这就是这个想法非常普遍的表达方式，而且这种表达方式是不必要的。